# **SEAN HEGARTY**

# INTEGRATED ARTWORKER

I've spent the past 20 years helping clients build strong, clear and consistent visual communications. My work displays a proven track record of inventive and compelling creative work across print and digital mediums.

During these challenging times, I'm looking to build strong relationships with Creative Directors, Designers and Account Managers to create compelling brands and a strong identity for companies.

I work with clients in creating video content posted on Instagram as part of integrated marketing campaigns.

I've also spent time managing a studio of a agency, which has given me an insight into how a successful project should move through an agency from conception to implementation.

# CONTACT

07855 456521

#### CAREER

# Senior Design Engineer at RAPP (February 2021 – December 2022)

Worked within the Creative Studio where traditional creative design craft is mixed with cutting edge technology to produce beautiful, personalised work at scale. It was a varied, hybrid role incorporating design, digital artwork, and front-end development disciplines.

- > Created artwork and templates for any medium, including press, POS, OOH, bespoke print, digital OOH, online banners and email
- > Produced work that adheres to brand guidelines and client requirements
- > Worked with online platforms, ensuring they're maintained with the most relevant user content
- > Worked closely with a varied team to ensure delivery of pixel perfect artwork
- > Timeline and code-based HTML animation

### Freelance Integrated Artworker (June 2013 – January 2021)

Enjoyed working for a wide-range of clients, from production and creative agencies, global corporate companies, start ups, charities and media companies. The clients I've recently worked with are listed below:

Clients I've worked for in chronological order include Performance 54, Identity Design, The Honest Brand, A Place for Rover, Splash Worldwide, Canary Wharf Group, Digitas, NKD Learning, Suburbia, Audio Network Limited, Effection, Me&Dave, Chelsea Football Club, Axa Insurance, Comic Relief, Sectorlight, Wallace Health, Quill Content, Mindshare, Health Circle, Digitas Health Lifebrands, Agora Health, Lambert Smith Hampton, Saatchi Health, Conrad Design Group, Lebara, Architas, Jones Lang LaSalle, Anderson Norton Design, Ampersand, FKA Studios, Lockton Insurance, Adstream, M&G Investments, Savills, Audience Media, The Football Association, G4S, Avery Dennison, Publicis Life Brands, BlackRock, Lusso, Initial, Law Creative and BrocklebankPenn.

# Head of Studio at Gungho Design (July 2010 – May 2013)

- > Managing 5 designers and a team of freelancers
- > Focus on designing bid documents and interactive presentations
- > Communicating a clear vision to the design team
- > Project managing multiple complex projects

# Artworker at UBS Global Asset Management (August 2008 – July 2010)

- > Produced artwork for the Business Development Team
- > Created regular financial and corporate reports
- > Worked under pressure to meet a succession of client deadlines

# Pitch Executive at CB Richard Ellis (August 2007 – August 2008)

- > Provided design support for the Pitch & Proposal Team
- > Prepared presentations for client pitches, such as interactive presentations, brochures, banners and moodboards
- > Project managed and designed large strategic proposal documents

#### **TESTIMONIALS**

It was an absolute pleasure to have Sean work as part of our team over the last 18 months. Sean has a can-do attitude and demonstrated a highly considered and thoughtful approach to all tasks undertaken. He is extremely professional, has very strong technical skills and made positive and valuable contributions to each project he worked on. Sean will be a very valuable asset to any company that employs him in the future.

Manuela Zwingmann Wood Group Marketing Manager (Brand & Residential) at Canary Wharf Group September 2019

Sean is a real pleasure to work with. Focused, self-motivated, pragmatic and skilled, he can always be trusted to 'just get it done' when you need it. As good alone as he is fitting into a well-established team, Sean is committed and adaptable across media old and new – what's more he's also a really nice guy.

#### **Tom Malt**

Creative Services
Director at BlackRock
August 2015

#### **CAREER** (continued)

# **Design Specialist** at **Deutsche Bank** (February 2001 – August 2007)

- > Designed and formatted bespoke and branded printed documents and on-screen presentations
- > Developed an understanding of colour management, styles, layers, grids, and master pages

#### **Various roles**

(1995 - 2001)

Employers included IPC Media, World Soccer 6ix's, and Marylebone Cricket Club

# **ATTRIBUTES**

- > Good eye for layout, with good retouching and visualising ability
- > Successfully delivered consistent brand and campaign roll-out
- > Collaborative skills to work with internal and external clients
- Combine creative flair with technical skill to produce the highest quality artworks and assets
- > Methodical approach to archiving images and artwork
- > Adaptable self-starter who can hit the ground running

# **SKILLS**

- Advanced knowledge of Indesign, Photoshop, Illustrator and Acrobat
- > Experience of using Sketch and Adobe XD to produce web assets
- Produced social media videos and 2D animation using After Effects
- > Knowledge of HTML, CSS (SASS) and basic JavaScript. Familiar with using Gulp, Node JS and Bootstrap in building websites
- > Microsoft Office proficiency
- > Typing (60wpm)

#### **EDUCATION**

BA Joint – Honours Degree in History & Politics (2:1) Leicester University (1989 – 1992)

#### **INTERESTS**

Design, travelling, eating out, photography, cycling, running, coding, exploring London.